Guide to the Gilbert-Cheever Family Papers
Yale University. Department of Manuscripts and Archives
- MEMORABILIA, PRINTED MATTER AND PHOTOGRAPHS, 1790, 1840-1882; Series III; 1 linear feet (3 boxes)
  - William Hinman Gilbert
    - Miscellaneous papers related to the Elm Green Academy of Granby, Connecticut (21), Circa 1859-1862 (Box 10, Folder 9)
    - U.S. Sanitary Commission: bulletin, "Letters from the Army of the Potomac" (1), 1864 (Box 10, Folder 10)
    - U.S. Christian Commission: "Statement for Army Meetings;" "Among the Wounded - Experiences of a Delegate" (2), 1864 June 1864 (Box 10, Folder 11)
    - U.S. Christian Commission: Second 1864 Report of the Committee of Maryland; record of Thanksgiving Service (2) (Box 10, Folder 12)
    - American Bible Society and Connecticut Bible Society: commissions, circulars, reports and specimen pages (35), 1865-1882 (Box 10, Folder 13)
    - Pamphlets and programs of the Classical and English Boarding School, Norwich, Vermont (9), 1867-1868 (Box 10, Folder 14)
  - Mary (Goodridge) Gilbert
    - Goodridge-Gilbert families: notes, clippings, photographs (5), Circa 1840-1850, undated (Box 10, Folder 15)
    - Bradford Academy: programs, catalogues (11), 1843-1852 (Box 11, Folder 16)
    - Bradford Academy: programs, catalogues (13), 1853-1880 (Box 11, Folder 17)
    - Essays and notes (36), [ca. 1840-1949?] (Box 11, Folder 18)
    - Catalogue, map relating to the Cheever family of San Francisco (2), 1862, undated (Box 11, Folder 19)
  - Charles Minor Gilbert
    - Autograph book, 1871 (Box 11, Folder 20)
    - Programs, invitations, photographs (39), 1873-1981 (Box 11, Folder 21)
    - Programs, invitations, photographs (41), 1877-1881 (Box 11, Folder 22)
    - Student essays (7), Circa 1876-1878 (Box 11, Folder 23)
    - Student notebook of lectures at Yale (1), [1874-1878?] (Box 11, Folder 24)
    - Obituary notice, from "Obituary Record of Graduates of Yale College" (1), 1881 (Box 11, Folder 25)
    - Charles M. Gilbert and George E. Gilbert: pins of honorary societies at Yale (7), [ca. 1875-1878?] (Box 11, Folder 26)
    - Charles M. Gilbert and George E. Gilbert: programs of the Hartford Public High School Classes of 1870-1875 (30) (Box 11, Folder 27)
  - George Edwards Gilbert
    General Note
    See also: box 11, folder 27
    - Autograph book (1), 1871 (Box 12, Folder 28)
    - Book of quotations (1), 1877 (Box 12, Folder 29)
    - Programs, invitations, grades, certificates (41), Circa 1875-1880 (Box 12, Folder 30)
    - Programs, invitations, photograph (17), Circa 1875-1880 (Box 12, Folder 31)
    - Programs, invitations, newspapers, photographs (19), Circa 1875-1880 (Box 12, Folder 32)
    - Newspapers (6), 1877-1880 (Box 12, Folder 33)
    - Student essays (20), Circa 1875-1878 (Box 12, Folder 34)
    - Obituary notice, from "Obituary Record of Graduates. of Yale College" (1), 1880 (Box 12, Folder 35)
- SERMONS OF WILLIAM HINMAN GILBERT, 1844-1864; Series IV; 2 linear feet (4 boxes)
  The SERMONS are arranged chronologically, with undated manuscripts arranged by biblical text. Incomplete sermons and fragments and one folder of sermon plans are located at the end of the series.
  - 1844 (4) (Box 13, Folder 1)
  - 1845 January-July (8) (Box 13, Folder 2)
  - 1845 August-December (11) (Box 13, Folder 3)
  - 1846 (12) (Box 13, Folder 4)
  - 1847 January-December (10) (Box 13, Folder 5-6)
  - 1848 January-December (12) (Box 13, Folder 7-8)
  - 1849 January-June (11) (Box 13, Folder 9)
  - 1849 July-December (10) (Box 13, Folder 10)
  - 1850 January-June (17) (Box 14, Folder 11)
  - 1850 July-December (15) (Box 14, Folder 12)
  - 1851 (8) (Box 14, Folder 13)
  - 1852 January-June (17) (Box 14, Folder 14)
  - 1852 July-December (14) (Box 14, Folder 15)
  - 1853 January-October (9) (Box 14, Folder 16)
  - 1853 November-December (8) (Box 15, Folder 17)
  - 1854 January-June (9) (Box 15, Folder 18)
  - 1854 July-December (6) (Box 15, Folder 19)
  - 1855-1856 (4) (Box 15, Folder 20-21)
  - 1857 (6) (Box 15, Folder 22)
  - 1858 January (3) (Box 15, Folder 23)
  - 1858 February-December (4) (Box 15, Folder 24)
  - 1859 January-1860 (6) (Box 16, Folder 25-27)
  - 1861 January-May (5) (Box 16, Folder 28)
  - 1861 June-December (6) (Box 16, Folder 29)
  - 1862-1863 (5) (Box 16, Folder 30-31)
  - 1863 (5) (Box 16, Folder 31)
  - 1864 (3) (Box 16, Folder 32)
  - Undated, arranged by biblical text (5) (Box 16, Folder 33)
  - Sermon outlines and notes, n.d., arranged by biblical text (14) (Box 16, Folder 34)
  - Undated - incomplete and fragments (9) (Box 16, Folder 35)
  - Sermon plans, 1844-1845 and n.d. (4) (Box 16, Folder 36)